IBRAHIM CONTEH

Houston Texas dallasb79@yahoo.com / 832.857.5511

SUMMARY

Vision-driven professional with expertise spanning technology sales, Salesforce administration, and Agile project management success for leading organizations Proven talent for aligning business strategy and objectives with established technology and sales management paradigms to drive continuous improvement and innovation. Results-focused thought leader with the ability to deliver high-impact technology solutions directly aligned with client needs, guide and lead Agile/Scrum ceremonies, provide updates and reporting to cross-functional stakeholders, and oversee Salesforce administration and configuration. Exceptionally dedicated professional with keen interpersonal, communication, and organizational skills, as well as change management, strategic planning, and resource allocation expertise.

SKILLS

- Technology Sales
- Salesforce Administration
- IT Operations Management
- Roadmap Development
- Opportunity Development
- Consulting

- Project Management
- Agile / Scrum / Waterfall / SAFe
- Business Analysis
- Customer Service
- Strategic Planning
- Issue Resolution

EXPERIENCE

SMALL BUSINESS ADVISOR / DELL TECHNOLOGIES - AUSTIN

05/2022 - 12/2022

- Generated new business for the company by handling up to 50 inbound and outbound calls and emails per day
 with both new and existing small business customers
- Identified opportunities to sell products and services to new customers and upgrade existing customers
- Leveraged strong interpersonal communication skills to build positive customer relationships and ensure the delivery of world-class customer service in line with the Dell sales model
- Gained a deep understanding of customer needs in order to recommend relevant business solutions, including desktops, laptops, servers, services, and accessories
- Maintained a strong focus on generating revenue and improving margins
- Aligned objectives and bridged communications with cross-functional teams, including product specialists, to proactively address client needs.

SALESFORCE ADMINISTRATOR / REDMOP ACADEMY - MARYLAND

06/2019 - 10/2021

- Partnered with colleagues to deliver effective security system configuration and maintenance for user accounts, custom objects, apps, roles, and profiles
- Modified and adapted fields, page layouts, record types, list views, reports, and dashboards
- Adhered to established policies while granting licenses and permissions to Salesforce users
- Enabled the reading, extraction, and loading of data from CSV files using Data Loader
- Ensured optimal data integrity by developing reports and dashboards for monitoring
- Contributed to knowledge management by producing field, process, and workflow documentation
- Responded to and resolved tickets in line with business service level agreements (SLAs)
- Coordinated and led sandbox refreshes and post-refresh setup and administration
- Fostered and maintained collaborative working relationships with colleagues, including liaising with developers, QAs, and others to efficiently resolve complex issues
- Conducted business application testing processes to ensure proper functionality and performance.

- Spearheaded the development of the WBS in collaboration with project team members, including defining and managing scope and change requests throughout the entire project lifecycle
- Strengthened project monitoring by establishing a logical framework, revamping KPIs, and developing a performance monitoring plan (PMP)
- Gained hands-on experience facilitating day-to-day project operations, including requesting project resources, allocating work plans, and coordinating schedules and activities
- Drafted and prepared detailed project status reports and communicated updates to leadership teams and stakeholders in a timely manner
- Verified alignment between completed work and the established project management methodology, framework, standards, and procedures.

IT COORDINATOR / UNITED STATES MARINE CORP - LUBBOCK

05/2013 - 05/2019

- Cultivated and maintained an Agile environment focused on collaboration, trust, and self-accountability
- Facilitated and led Agile ceremonies, such as iteration planning, iteration reviews, retrospectives, and daily standups, to support the success of the IT organization
- Engaged with cross-functional stakeholders and delivered value in collaboration with the Product Owner
- Mitigated risks and eliminated obstacles through monitoring, escalation, and resolution, directly contributing to the achievement of business and project goals
- Guided the team in project estimation and sizing as well as maintaining a healthy product backlog
- Charted the successful development and implementation of dashboards and metrics for reporting project progress.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.SC: BIOLOGY University of Texas at the Permian Basin - Odessa, TX, USA

12/2019

Salesforce Certified Administrator

Certified Scrum Master

Technical Proficiencies:

SFDC Classic, Lightning, Sales Cloud, Service Cloud, Salesforce Communities, Third-Party Integration, Business Automation, MS Dynamics CRM, Data Management, Technical Support, MS Excel, ServiceNow

INTERESTS

Football, Soccer, photography, tennis

LANGUAGES

English